Finding Aid for James Foster Foundation records, 1950-1963
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
James Foster Foundation records 1950-1963
James Foster Foundation.
0.5 linear feet
88420 Bm 2
Correspondence, reports, and financial statements, dealing with the foundation's support of marriage counseling, child guidance programs, and other social programs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Paul Proud Jr. (Donor No. 4075 ) in 1963.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
Founded in 1950 by Clarice N. Foster as a memorial to her late husband, James Foster of Ann Arbor, Michigan, the James Foster Foundation was established to "promote the welfare of mankind through educational, charitable, and religious pursuits, with particular emphasis on the general welfare of the people of Michigan." During the thirteen years of its corporate life, the foundation made grants to organizations generally described as charitable, educational, religious, scientific, and literary, or to civic organizations concerned with social welfare. In addition, it provided scholarships and loans and other assistance to students at the University of Michigan. The Foundation ceased operation in 1963 after its funds had been distributed to various charitable organizations.
The James Foster Foundation records (0.5 linear feet) document the organization's charitable activities between 1950 and 1963, with the bulk covering the period 1950-1956.
The collection is arranged into folders containing background clippings, bylaws and governing documents, board minutes, financial materials, and correspondence. In addition, there are a few files relating to specific activities of the Foundation, notably the evaluative research in social work conducted by David French and the Michigan Welfare League, a marriage counseling program for Washtenaw County, and a Michigan Foundation's conference sponsored in 1954.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Charitable uses, trusts and foundations--Michigan.; Child welfare--Michigan.; Endowments--Michigan.; James Foster Foundation (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Marriage counseling.; Michigan Foundations (Organization); Michigan Welfare League.; Michigan reconnaissance study on evaluative research in social work.; Social service--Michigan.
- Corporate records
  - Background clippings, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Bylaws and governing documents, 1950-1961 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1950-1963 (Box 1)
  - Financial materials, 1950-1963 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1956, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Real estate (Box 1)
  - Topical Files
    - French, David G. and the Michigan Welfare League, 1949-1955 (Box 1)
    - French, David G. and the Michigan Welfare League, Book Chapters of Evaluative Research and Social Work (Box 1)
    - Marriage Counseling Service, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Foundations Conference, 1954 (Box 1)